[radio static]
[man 1] I'm a Spurs fan, he's…
[overlapping chatter]
[woman 1] I've got a date
with a new guy next week.
[man 2] I think we need some
proper leadership
for young people.
[man 3] Who would you ideally
replace him with?
[overlapping chatter continues]
[woman 2] I don't have any unclaimed…
[man 4] …getting youthful…
[man 5] …a black hatchback…
[overlapping chatter continues]
[man 6] I need my money,
I've got a mortgage,
I've got bills to pay…
[man 7] …every WhatsApp group.
[woman 3] Why don't I meet you
at the car park?
[man 8] …learn to pirouette
like a prima ballerina.
…tell her one more
time where our printer is.
It doesn't move.
[overlapping chatter continues]
You wouldn't have
to replay the whole fight
if you'd just listened to me
in the first place.
[man 9] These supplements make me feel
like more of a man than ever.
The manager's been watching us
on cameras from his office.
[man 10] Don't you think
a lie like that is dangerous?
[overlapping chatter continues]
[man 11] Listen.
This is a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
[overlapping chatter continues]
If anyone finds out about this,
we're both dead, that's it.
[woman 4] I'll be there in three hours.
[notifications chime]
[woman 5] When the King of Glory comes…
[overlapping chatter crescendos]
-[chatter stops]
-["Paradise" playing]
[child playing xylophone]
[woman] You're getting good at that.
I've got a very big day in court today
and I'm a little nervous.
[boy] I've got football
and I hate football.
[woman laughs]
[woman] Come on, get yourself ready.
[boy] I've been ready for ages.
[woman] Oh, yeah?
Have you changed your insulin pod?
-Yep.
-How are your numbers?
-[mobile phone chimes]
-[boy] Ninety-six.
All good.
[man]
♪ But this time it's real ♪
♪ It's something that I feel ♪
♪ If it feels like paradise ♪
♪ Running through
Your bloody veins ♪
♪ You know it's love
Heading your way ♪
♪ If it feels like paradise ♪
♪ Running through
Your bloody veins ♪
♪ You know it's love
Heading your way ♪
-♪ My time ♪
-[chorus] ♪ My time ♪
♪ My t-t-t-t-time ♪
♪ Well, it's a never-ending
Helter-skelter… ♪
One, two, and…
three.
♪ My boom-boom heart ♪
♪ It's a beating
It's a thumping ♪
Let's go.
-♪ I know you heard it… ♪
-[song ends]
[boy] We did this fundraising thing
where we got to throw
wet sponges at Mr Pearson.
-[woman] Really?
-Yeah.
[woman chuffs]
-[woman 2] See you later!
-[chuckles]
[woman] What about going in
on your own today, hmm?
Mmm-mmm.
Come on, just give it a go.
Hmm?
But I like it when you walk me in.
[chuckles] I know
but it's good to try new things.
Remember when you were afraid
to go ice skating?
I think you'd be the one to miss it.
-[boy grunts]
-Whoa.
I love you.
[kisses] I'm proud of you.
And don't forget to check
your glucose numbers.
I love you, monkey.
-Love you, Mum.
-[woman blows kisses]
[mobile phone ringing]
[automated voice] Ted McBain calling.
[earphone beeps]
-Hi, Ted.
-[Ted] Morning.
They've moved the witness pick-up time.
It's now 10:15.
Okay, got it.
[Ted] Does that leave you
enough time to run in?
Yeah, no problem.
[Ted sighs]
Can we talk about last night?
I thought you were having
a good time and then--
[sighs] You said all you needed to say.
You don't wanna have kids. I have Noah.
And that's that.
[sighs] I said I needed to think about--
Look, I understand your position.
Really, if I didn't have Noah,
I'm not sure
if I would get involved with
someone who has a child.
It's okay.
[Ted] You're trying to argue my point
-but it's not even my point.
-Ted, I gotta run.
I'll see you at the office.
-[Ted] Maia--
-[call ends]
[exhales]
["Heart of Glass" playing]
[woman] ♪ Once I had a love
And it was a gas ♪
♪ Soon turned out
Had a heart of glass ♪
♪ Seemed like the real thing
Only to find ♪
♪ Mucho mistrust
Love's gone behind ♪
-[song stops]
-[mobile phone ringing]
[automated voice] Flora Gibson calling.
-[earphone beeps]
-Maia Marten.
[Flora] Maia, the police are here.
You said they wouldn't take my devices.
They've got my computer--
-Flora, stop.
-I don't know what to do!
-Take a breath.
-[Flora breathes deeply]
Good.
Never talk to the police without me, okay?
[Flora] Okay.
Your husband is just trying to scare you.
[Flora] Well, I'm the one
telling the truth, Maia!
He's the criminal.
[Maia] Listen to me.
99% of defending yourself
is telling the right story.
Controlling the narrative.
[Flora] So what's the other 1%?
[exhales] Being innocent.
Listen, Flora, I gotta run.
["Heart of Glass" resumes]
♪ In between ♪
♪ What I find is pleasing ♪
♪ And I'm feeling fine ♪
♪ Love is so confusing ♪
♪ There's no peace of mind ♪
♪ If I fear I'm losing you ♪
♪ It's just no good ♪
♪ You teasing like you do ♪
[both panting]
♪ Once I had a love
And it was a gas ♪
♪ Soon turned out
Had a heart of glass ♪
♪ Seemed like the real thing
But I was so blind ♪
♪ Mucho mistrust
Love's gone-- ♪
-[song ends]
-[mobile phone ringing]
[automated voice] Noah calling.
-[earphone beeps]
-[panting]
Okay, what did we forget this time?
[caller] I haven't forgotten
a thing, Maia.
Blessed with a perfect memory.
Who is this? Why are you on
my son's phone?
[caller] Because I have your son.
-What?
-[caller] Here in the park.
At the Temple of Venus.
Who is this?
[caller] Think of me as
a force for change.
You're stuck in a rut.
Looks like you've ordered
the same chicken ramen
every week for the last five years.
Helen, is that you?
[caller chuckles] Listen to you.
Grasping for explanations.
No, I think you've got my son's phone
and you're pulling a prank.
[caller] Then why are you
walking towards the temple?
[breathing heavily]
-[gasps]
-[speaks indistinctly]
[caller] If you don't believe me,
Noah can tell you himself.
Noah, say hi to Mummy.
[Noah] Mum, he's got me
chocolate chip ice cream.
-I love it.
-Noah, where are you?
[Noah] At the temple. Are you here?
Stay exactly where you are. Don't move.
[Noah] I've got to go now.
Your friend said we'll see you later.
No, Noah, you need to get away from him.
-[line disconnects]
-["Heart of Glass" resumes]
[switches music off]
[tense music playing]
[panting]
[distant siren blares]
[Maia grunts]
-My God! Why'd she do that?
-[woman] So rude.
[breathing heavily]
[woman] Hey, get off him!
-What are you doing?
-Sorry.
Are you all right, darling?
[mobile phone chimes]
[man] Yeah, it's like a bush or something.
Ah, here you are.
[woman] So sorry I'm late.
I couldn't find you.
[man] Don't worry about it.
Noah?
-[tense music continues]
-[woman] Is she okay?
[echoes] Noah?
[mobile phone ringing]
Where are you?
[scam caller] Miss Marten,
you have won £100,000.
[ends call]
[mobile phone ringing]
Are you here?
Hello?
[caller] Hello.
Now, you listen to me. This game is over.
Where are you?
Maia, take a breath.
If you lay a finger on him,
I swear to God I'm gonna kill you.
If we're gonna do this,
you need to calm down.
How dare you tell me to calm down?
[breathing heavily]
Were you a defendant in one of my cases?
-If you were--
-You have a logical mind.
But sometimes logic isn't enough.
[indistinct police radio chatter]
Never talk to the police.
Isn't that what you told Flora?
This is a very simple game.
It's like snakes and ladders.
You follow my rules
and Noah lives.
Disobey, he dies.
[breathing heavily]
Rule number one,
you talk to nobody but me,
on the phone, on the street.
Nobody. Understood?
-Understood?
-Yes. Yes, I understand.
The second rule, you do
what I say when I say.
You do not bore me.
["The Entertainer" playing]
["The Entertainer" continues playing]
[Maia] Are you still in the park?
[caller] No, we're almost home.
Aren't we, Noah?
So let's begin.
Do you know the men's swimming pond?
Yes.
Run to it.
[tense music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
Now look in the red bin.
[tense music playing]
[music stops]
Do you have it?
There's a package inside.
[Maia breathing heavily]
Your star witness,
Mr Radian Tafa,
is under heavy protection
at the Excelsus Hotel.
Today is trial day.
At 10:15, he's gonna be
transported to the Old Bailey
to stand witness against my employer.
But that won't happen
because you're gonna kill him first.
You're too late.
They moved him last night.
He's not even there.
I've heard so many grand
things about Maia Marten
and her ability to spin her own reality
in the courtroom.
But here you are
telling little butterfly lies.
I know you're one of six people
with access to Tafa today,
because you wrote it in an email.
[swimmer laughing]
If you're one of Boyd's men,
I can get you immunity.
You can testify, we can fix everything.
Maia.
I'm a freelancer, a specialist.
Okay, whatever he's paying you,
I'll double it.
I've seen your bank balance.
You can't afford me.
I can get you the money, trust me.
Don't bore me!
But why me?
Oh, you know why, Maia.
[unsettling musical sting]
I can't kill someone.
I think you can.
And you want Noah to live, don't you?
Noah has nothing to do with this! Please--
-[shrill electronic whine]
-[gasps]
-[whining continues]
-[Maia groaning]
[bird squawks]
[panting]
[mobile phone chimes]
I'm sorry I bored you.
I'll do whatever you say.
-[Noah] Thank you, Mummy.
-Noah?
-I like your friend.
-[static whines]
Can he be my daddy, please?
-What?
-Can he be my daddy, please?
[distorted] Can he be my daddy, please?
Hello? Are you all right?
[caller chuckles] Isn't AI amazing?
Irresponsible to have unleashed it
on the general public, really.
You should check his glucose numbers.
[beeping]
Thirty-two's quite low, isn't it?
You… You hacked his insulin dispenser?
I gave him an extra dose.
And now he's in a hypoglycaemic coma.
[shudders]
Another full dose would kill him.
But this drip is quite slow.
He should survive for about an hour.
-[Maia gasps]
-The coma is reversible
with an injection of glucagon,
which I know you always carry with you.
You're going to kill Tafa
and only then will I tell you
where Noah is.
[sniffles]
[breath trembles]
Now, text Ted.
Tell him you need to see Tafa
for some last-minute trial advice.
[sniffs, exhales]
Let me send that for you.
[breathing heavily]
From where you're standing,
it's just over five miles
to the Excelsus Hotel.
-At your pace…
-Wait…
…you can cover that in under an hour.
You want me to run?
Keeping you running keeps you
where I can track you.
Stops you from talking
to anyone you shouldn't.
Please.
And you know what happens
if you break the rules.
-Stop!
-[watch vibrates]
-[beeping]
-Tick, tick, tick, tick…
[child's laughter echoes]
[dog barking]
[birds' cries echo]
-[exhales]
-Maia?
[beeping]
You're wasting time.
Maia!
[tense music playing]
[reporter] There's a palpable
air of expectation
here at the Old Bailey today
on the opening day of Tommy Boyd's trial
for double murder.
Mr Boyd, an alleged crime boss
in south London,
is accused of murdering
Sasha Summerhill and Anita Patel
after an altercation
at a night spot in Romford.
[beeping]
[Maia panting]
[tense music playing]
Oh. Hey! Hey, Maia.
Hey! Oh, I'm so glad I ran into you.
I wanted to apologise for Weston's party.
I-I told him to ask the whole class, and…
[caller] God, I loathe parental hypocrisy.
But he binned Noah's invite
when I wasn't looking.
[chuckles] You know how silly boys can be.
[caller] Call her a bitch.
It's what you're thinking.
…not talking to each other.
-Do it.
-I did ask Weston why.
-And he said--
-Bitch.
[woman] Oh, my God. How rude!
[woman 2] What's she on about?
[caller] Doesn't that feel
good, to be yourself?
-[Alice] What's that about?
-[woman 1] Are you all right?
Keep going straight, down College Lane.
[Maia panting]
[monitor beeping]
Your heart rate is elevated.
You need to pace yourself.
Under-16 pentathlon champ.
You'd do anything to win, wouldn't you?
Is that immigrant drive
or having your father as your coach?
What was it he said to you?
"Control your breath,
master your fear."
-Good advice.
-You don't know me.
That's where you're wrong, Maia.
I know you better than you know yourself.
[suspenseful music playing]
[indistinct overlapping chatter]
-[women wailing]
-Hey, stop!
[women wailing]
[Maia panting]
Do you know what piqued
my interest in you?
-[brakes squealing]
-[Maia grunts]
[cyclist] You okay?
[caller] Why would such
an attractive woman
choose to have a child on her own?
You've been running
from your past, haven't you?
Hard to lose a parent to violent crime.
Harder still when
the killer is your mother.
All those birthdays on your own
while she was in prison.
She didn't do it.
She was innocent.
Why lie to yourself, Maia?
I'm sure he abused her terribly.
I'm not gonna…
I'm not gonna talk about
my private life with you.
[caller] Well, opening up is a process.
We'll get there.
But tell me, is that
why you became a lawyer
to assert your will over violent men?
-I became a lawyer to--
-[dog barking]
-[gasps, grunts]
-[woman] I'm so sorry.
To put psychopaths like you in jail.
[laughs]
[caller] Cross the street
and go down Kentish Town Road.
Just a little reminder,
you've got 53 minutes,
10 seconds remaining.
[timer beeping]
-[suspenseful music plays]
-[Maia panting]
[indistinct chatter]
[man] Let me know…
Why are you slowing down? What's going on?
It's crowded. Everyone's on their phones.
[woman] They know she was fortunate.
[caller] That's the world we live in.
Nobody meets your eye,
all staring at a device.
Mind you, Kentish town at rush hour
is always full of nutters.
So you live locally.
Huh! Don't try to be clever, Maia.
I recognise the gun.
Oh, really?
Ruger LCP,
the same model your employer used
to murder those women.
No, you've missed the point.
It's the exact same gun.
You and I are gonna drive
the conspiracy nuts wild.
But I will give you this.
No one but you could have
got Tafa to squeal.
That was impressive.
The rest of your case is pathetic.
So once you've killed Tafa,
my client will walk.
[Maia] You sick prick.
[caller] Don't torment yourself.
Tafa's no angel.
No, but Tafa doesn't rape
and murder women like your boss.
Ah, there she is, the fearless
champion of wronged women.
Will that be the title of your
self-righteous autobiography?
[Maia] Are you some sort of woman hater?
I'm gonna give those murdered women
a voice in front of a jury,
then the law will come for you.
I am the law, Maia.
Might is right these days.
I know you didn't go home.
-What?
-You said you took Noah home,
but you can't have.
I heard piano music and voices.
Maia, you're remedial.
And you must have an accomplice.
You didn't have time
to drop Noah's bag yourself,
which means there's someone out--
You're boring me again, Maia.
-[insect buzzing]
-[glass tinkling]
[mobile phone ringing]
[automated voice] Noah's school calling.
[AI Maia] Hello?
Hi, Maia. Er, this is Malcolm Brady.
Erm, look, Noah wasn't
at registration this morning.
-Hello? Hello? He--
-Is everything okay?
[AI Maia] Oh, I completely
forgot to call you.
-[keyboard clacking]
-I'm sorry.
He's feeling poorly
and I kept him at home.
[Malcolm] Oh, I see.
Do you mind letting us know
in future so we don't worry?
[AI Maia] I'm glad he has a teacher
who worries over him.
Sorry, I'd talk more, but I've got to run.
Bye.
[caller] That should buy us some time.
Let's go.
[man] I'll be there by 12:00.
-[beeping]
-[caller] Tick, tick, tick.
[tyres screech]
What are you doing?
Look where you're going!
What is going on with people today?
[customer] Just got lucky.
[overlapping chatter]
Go straight ahead.
[workman] Hey, what's the rush, darling?
[caller] Where are you going?
I said straight ahead.
[Maia] It's gonna be quicker
along the canal.
[caller] Remember the rules, Maia.
You do what I say.
Trust me, I'm the one
who actually runs in the city.
[street vendors yelling]
[vendor] Sale!
[overlapping chatter]
[speaks other language]
[woman gasps]
[male pedestrian in English]
She's a thief!
-[caller] What was that?
-I bumped into someone.
[overlapping chatter continues]
[vendor 1] I see you're
interested. Come on, fella.
[vendor 2] They're making it right…
[pedestrian yells]
-Hey, my phone!
-[man] Oi!
She's got my phone! You lot, stop her!
Hey, come back here!
[panting]
She's got my phone!
Give me back my phone!
[indistinct chattering in other language]
[caller, in English] I dislike
it when you're quiet.
What's on your mind?
What the hell are you doing?
[man speaks in other language]
[in English] I'm wondering whether or not
Noah has spoiled his dinner
with all that ice cream.
You've got a sense of humour.
Do you think your beautiful
boy will inherit that?
I know Noah's father was only a donor,
-but will he ever meet him?
-No.
Probably for the best.
Fathers are tricky, aren't they?
[boyfriend] All right, now
this angle… this looks good.
-[gasps]
-[boy] What are you doing?
-Stop! Bring that back!
-[girl] She took my phone!
-[boy] Yo!
-[girl] Oi! Stop her!
[boy] That's my girl's phone!
Stop!
-Stop!
-[people exclaim]
Stop!
That's my girl's phone! Hey, stop!
Please…
You all right, love?
-Oi! Hey, hey, hey!
-[boy] Oi!
That's my girl's phone!
-Oi! Oi!
-[builder] Whoa!
-What are you talking about?
-That's my phone!
That's my girl's phone!
You've got the wrong guy!
Oi! You got the wrong guy!
She's got my phone.
-[grunts] Are you kidding me?
-Sorry.
[Maia panting]
[woman talks indistinctly]
[mid-tempo song playing on speakers]
[woman] Hey, watch out!
[Maia grunts] No!
Shit!
[woman] What's wrong with you?
-[child crying]
-Watch where you're going!
[woman soothes child]
[caller] Maia?
Maia?
[Maia] I fell.
You okay?
I hurt my knee.
Is it serious?
[sighs] As if you care.
Oh, but I do care.
You're very precious to me.
And to Ted.
He was really upset
by your conversation this morning.
You've hacked into Ted's phone.
An insurance policy,
in case you were
foolish enough to contact him.
Hmm?
You know what he told
his friend Alan yesterday?
He said he feels something with you
that he's never felt with a woman before.
But I wonder if you might
just be toying with him.
All those flirty texts,
which you never follow up on.
You know, I, um…
I found a folder on your laptop.
You thought you deleted it.
But your digital hygiene is terrible.
Were those photos for him?
[breathing heavily]
[breathing sounds intensify]
You little piece of shit.
You perv. You freaking perv.
You're so avoidant, Maia. It's unhealthy.
Have you ever seen a therapist?
-Oh, wait. Yes, Dr Katz.
-Shit.
But that didn't last for long.
Painful, was it?
But we all need to share
our secrets with someone.
Why did you use an encrypted app
to communicate with your mother?
And what does this message
mean where she says,
"We're forever bonded
by what happened that night"?
[insect buzzing]
Did you see the body?
Or did she shelter you from it?
"What's bred in the bone
outs in the flesh."
Do you know what that
expression means, Maia?
It means you can't escape who you are.
Leave me alone.
[caller] That's why I think
you've got what it takes.
You're worried
that you're like your mother,
and she was a killer.
And you think you are, too.
[Maia] She wasn't a killer. You're wrong.
Come on, Maia, tell me the truth.
All I want is honesty.
What happened to your father?
-Ugh! Get out of my--
-[tyres screech]
[woman screams]
[electronic whine]
[whooshing]
[paramedic, distorted]
I'm just checking your eyes.
[caller] Maia.
[paramedic] You were in an accident.
[paramedic] Everything's going to be fine.
Maia, where are you?
[paramedic] I'm getting you
to hospital, okay?
Everything's going to be fine.
[caller] Are you okay? Maia, wake up!
[paramedic] Okay?
How… How long have I been…
You were hit by a car.
You've been unconscious for a few minutes.
Well…
[caller] Ah, I'm glad to have you back.
Noah…
But you've lost a lot of time.
The clock is ticking.
I can't do this.
I need to rest.
[caller] Come on, Maia,
you're a fighter. Fight!
[Maia groans] I have to run.
-Oh! Oh! Er…
-I can't do this,
I need to run.
I need to run. I need to run.
-Listen…
-I'm gonna get you a sedative.
I need to go. Dammit.
-Please calm down!
-Let me go!
I'm trying to help you!
-What are you doing?
-[siren blaring]
-You should be in hospital!
-[passer-by] Oh, bugger!
Stop! Stop the van!
[tyres screech]
[woman] Hey!
[caller] You have 35 minutes,
20 seconds remaining.
I need more time.
I need more time. I won't make it.
There is no more time.
[retches]
Witness protection will pick up Tafa
at 10:15 precisely.
If you're going to save Noah,
you need to be there 15 minutes before.
[unsettling music plays]
[unsettling music continues]
[panting]
[beeping]
Ah, you've got to pick up the pace, Maia.
[man grunts] What do
you think you're doing?
[ticket barrier alarm blaring]
[train doors beeping]
[baby crying]
[announcer] …City Line train to Barking.
The next station is Farringdon.
[overlapping chatter]
[shrill screeching]
[caller] What's that noise?
-[baby crying]
-[headset beeps]
[ambient noise becomes muffled]
-[crying intensifies]
-[caller winces] Ow!
[crying continues on headset]
It's okay.
[mother] Aww!
It's all right.
It's okay.
[commuter talks indistinctly]
[caller grunts softly]
[exhales]
[commuter] Do you know
if this train goes to Bank?
[map beeping]
[caller] You're going very fast.
What's going on?
I hope you're not breaking the rules.
No, I'm just trying to make up time.
Did your mother ever share with you
what it was like to take a human's life?
-No.
-Prepare yourself.
There's more blood in the human body
than you can fathom.
And when it spills out,
you think it must be done.
But it just keeps coming.
-[commuter preaching]
-I'm not interested!
[commuter] …will have everlasting life,
so that you can spend eternity in heaven.
Not in hellfire.
Do you want to give up
the desires of the flesh,
and all its fleshly lusts,
to spend your time with God the Father?
[commuter 2] Watch it!
[commuter] This is your opportunity today
to repent and turn over a new leaf.
[continues indistinctly]
Okay.
[caller] Why are you slowing down again?
[Maia] Traffic.
You don't want me to get run over, do you?
[announcer] The next station
is Farringdon.
Change for the Elizabeth line
and National Rail services.
[beeping steadily]
[caller] You're not running, are you?
I am.
-Are you on a train?
-What? No.
Maia, do you think I'm stupid?
-What?
-Think about your boy.
-[Maia] Hello? Hello?
-[both] Yeah!
[static hisses]
-Hello?
-[static hisses]
Hello?
[automated voice] Connection lost.
[device chimes]
[gasps]
[Maia] My phone! My phone!
My phone!
-No, no, no, no!
-[both laugh mockingly]
I need my phone!
[panting] No, no!
["Running" playing]
[man] ♪ Wake me up
When the shooting starts ♪
♪ I'm gonna pack my bag… ♪
[man] What are you doing?
-[tyres screech, horn blares]
-[taxi driver] Careful!
♪ Burn, burn, burn ♪
♪ Burn, burn, burn
Burn, burn ♪
♪ Let it burn, burn, burn
Burn, burn, burn ♪
♪ Let it burn ♪
♪ Oh my God ♪
♪ I was playing Lucy when
I should have played God ♪
-[horn blaring]
-[driver cries out]
♪ Only Lucy
Gonna hold me tight ♪
[tyres screech]
[cab driver] Watch out, love!
Get off the road!
♪ I was playing Lucy when
I should have played God ♪
[dogs barking]
♪ Looking to the left
Should've been right ♪
-Come on!
-[horn blares]
[tyres screech, brakes squeal]
♪ Running, running, running
Running, running ♪
♪ Running, running
♪ From the grey thoughts
In my mind ♪
[horns blaring]
♪ Running, running, running
Running, running ♪
♪ Running, running
♪ From the grey thoughts
In my mind ♪
♪ Don't blow me high ♪
♪ I said blue back, baby ♪
♪ On the telephone ♪
♪ I'm in the calling light
Now, baby ♪
♪ Won't you leave me alone? ♪
♪ Bitch, I'm running ♪
♪ Running, running
Running, running, running ♪
♪ Running, running, running ♪
♪ From the grey thoughts
In my mind ♪
♪ Bitch, I'm running ♪
♪ Running, running, running
Running, running, running ♪
-[female commuter yells]
-Stop her!
♪ Running, running, running ♪
♪ From the grey thoughts
In my mind ♪
♪ Don't blow me high ♪
-[gasps]
-[music ends]
[announcer] …Central line
train to Barking.
The next station is Liverpool Street.
[panting heavily]
[train accelerating]
[panting]
[continues panting]
[Maia] Hey.
[thief 1] What?
My phone.
-What's she saying?
-[exhales sharply]
-Whoa, hey.
-Give me my phone.
Huh, what phone?
Huh? [chuckling]
What phone?
Give it to me now.
-Eh… Huh?
-[laughs]
[pouch unzips]
-[groans]
-[thief 2] Yo, what the heck?
Chill out, lady!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
[thief 2] Bro, she got a gun, man!
[thief 1] What the hell?
[commuters gasp]
[woman] Oh, my God.
[Maia panting]
You have no idea what you've done.
[radio chirps, indistinct radio chatter]
[announcer] The next station
is Liverpool Street.
Oh, shit.
[male commuter] Is she all right?
Change for the Central and Circle lines,
the Elizabeth line, London Overground…
[thief 1] She's got a friggin' gun, man.
[officer] You okay?
Ma'am?
Stop, please, ma'am!
[commuter grunts]
[officer] Pull the emergency brake now!
-[emergency brake squeals]
-[commuters yelling]
[man] Sorry.
[officer] What are you doing?
Don't go in there!
Stop!
Open up!
Please, ma'am. Open up!
Open this door! Open this door now!
Open up, please, ma'am!
Open up now!
[panting]
-[train whirring]
-[crackling]
[train wheels clack]
[train engine whining]
[screams]
[timer beeping]
Hey. Hey!
Hey, can you help me?
Would you get off your goddamn phone?
I need some help.
-[man grunts]
-[Maia strains, grunts]
[man] That's it.
[announcer] CCTV is in use
throughout London Underground.
[Maia panting]
[sirens blaring]
[female officer] Police! Move out the way!
[indistinct police radio chatter]
[officer 1] Back!
Move, move, move!
[officer 2] Evacuate the station!
[officer 3] Police!
-♪ Kumbaya ♪
-[officer 4] Move back!
[officer 5] Police! Get back!
[breath shudders]
Come on, come on, come on.
[mobile phone beeps]
[Maia's breath trembles]
[officer] Can we have a word
with you, love?
Sure.
Sure, sure, sure. [sniffles]
Sorry.
Is this, er, private property?
I was just looking for some quiet place
to call my boyfriend.
Put your hands in the air
and lean against the wall.
-[horn beeps]
-[cyclist whoops]
-[officer] Stop! Stop! Police!
-[tense music playing]
Stop! Police!
[cyclists shouting indistinctly]
[officer] Stop!
Police! Get out my way!
Stop! Stay where you are!
[woman] Watch out!
[people clamouring]
[female cyclist shouts indistinctly]
[upbeat song playing]
[horn blares]
Oh, my goodness! I almost hit you!
[horns blaring]
[officer] Hey, stop!
[music ends]
[panting]
[mobile phone beeps]
[sombre music playing]
[Maia sobs]
[priest] Are you all right?
It's often those
who are afraid to ask for help
who need it the most.
I just need a moment of peace.
Would you like to confess?
If you're in pain,
there are always options.
[Maia whimpers]
His blood is our blood,
and He bled for our sins.
Did you know there's more blood
in the human body than you can fathom?
[suspenseful music playing]
[door opens]
[gasps]
[choir singing]
[mobile phone ringing]
[automated voice] Unknown caller calling.
Hello? I'm… I'm sorry.
I'm sorry someone stole my phone.
[scam caller] Hello,
Miss Marten, this is Harry.
I've got some wonderful news.
Are you as excited as I am?
Yes.
I am really pleased to tell
you that you've won a prize
of £100,000,
brought to you by Proton Economics.
I can assure you, any personal details
that you share with us
will be completely safe.
-[shrill whine]
-We are a member
of RCCP Online Security Forum.
I know you're listening.
Of course I'm listening, ma'am.
No, not you.
Him.
[scam caller] Sorry, who?
I don't understand.
What are you talking about?
I just need your bank details
and I can get it all sorted.
I can do this, do you hear me?
[scam caller] What?
[Maia] Just give me a chance.
This is your big chance, Miss Marten.
-You're gonna be rich.
-[ends call]
-Hello?
-[caller breathes deeply]
Hello?
[caller breathes deeply]
-Come on, come on, come on.
-[inhales deeply]
-[caller exhales]
-Hello?
It's over.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
I can still do this. I'll do anything.
-You broke the rules.
-I had no choice.
They stole my phone.
[caller] You waved a gun around in public.
And now the police
have a call out for you.
You're useless to me now.
I'm not useless. I can still do this.
Please.
[caller] No.
I'll have to handle it myself.
A lot of people are gonna die,
-not just Noah.
-[button clicks]
-[beeping]
-It's gonna be messy
and that's your fault.
I'm never wrong,
but I was wrong about you.
No, listen.
[panting]
You were only wrong about one thing.
It wasn't my mother who killed my father,
it was me.
[Maia panting]
Tell me.
When my father was drunk,
he became an animal.
[chuckles ruefully] The things he did…
One night I came into the kitchen,
and he was drinking milk from a carton.
His fists were still wet with blood.
My mother's blood.
I aimed my target pistol at him
and he wasn't even afraid.
It's like he thought
nothing could hurt him.
So he died surprised.
I never told this to anyone. Only you.
[sighs]
Thank you.
So your mother went to jail
so you could have a life.
Yes.
[Maia panting]
Please give me another chance.
[panting]
You have 15 minutes.
Thank you.
[suspenseful music playing]
[church bells toll]
[beeping]
[indistinct chatter]
[brass band playing]
[caller] You should be able
to see the hotel now.
You've got plenty of time.
[timer beeping]
Shit. Police on the bridge.
[caller] The whole area is crawling.
You have to go to Blackfriars Bridge.
[panting]
I'll never make it.
Just stop the drip.
We're in this together now.
[caller] Yes, we're a team now,
but remember what your father said.
Fear is a stronger
motivator than love. Hmm?
Police coming from
the other direction too.
Take a hard left down the stairs.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Maia panting]
[map beeping]
The police are on their way
to Blackfriars.
Gotta be quick, Maia.
[sirens wailing]
-[officer] One Alpha Five.
-No, no, no.
[caller] Head to the underpass
to your left.
Waterloo is the only bridge
that's still open.
If you keep this pace, you can do it.
[Maia] It's half a mile
in the wrong direction.
I can't do that.
-Use the fear, Maia.
-Fuck you!
[Maia panting]
[groans]
Police car coming towards you.
[siren blaring]
[coughs]
[vendor] Hey, hey, hey! Stop, thief!
-Stop!
-[caller] Up the steps.
Take a left.
Cross the street.
Take the alleyway behind King's College.
Now go left on the Strand.
[timer beeping]
More police around the next corner.
There's a shortcut
that gets you onto the bridge.
Take a left now through Somerset House.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Maia panting]
[helicopter blades whirring]
[caller] There's a single policeman
coming towards you.
Blend into the crowd.
Twenty metres.
Fifteen metres.
Ten metres.
Five metres.
[passers-by chatting indistinctly]
[woman] My God, he was so cute!
-[women whooping, laughing]
-[woman] Sorry, sorry.
-[officer] Control, suspect…
-No, no, no.
-[people clamouring]
-[woman] She's got a gun!
[man] Come on, go!
[dispatcher] …believed to be
armed with a black handgun…
Take your hand off that!
[dispatcher] Suspect is Maia Marten.
Take it easy. Take it easy.
-[caller] Take his radio.
-I don't need your help.
-[officer] Please, ma'am.
-Get back! Get back!
-Get back!
-[crowd clamours, screams]
[officer] Please, drop the weapon.
Give me your radio. On your knees now!
I said, give me the radio.
-[sirens wailing]
-[gunshot]
[crowd screaming]
[caller] Multiple police cars
incoming, Maia.
Armed units.
[tyres squealing]
-You're trapped!
-[officer 1] Armed police!
[officer 2] Armed police!
-[officer 3] Police, drop the weapon!
-[caller] It's over!
[police shout orders indistinctly]
[Maia panting]
[officer] Failure to comply,
we will use lethal force!
[caller] I'm sorry that Noah's
gonna die without you.
No, that's not gonna happen.
Ma'am. Let me help you.
Shut the fuck up!
[officer 1] Whatever trouble you're in,
we can still fix it.
[officer 2] Drop the weapon!
Put the gun down!
[caller] What are you doing?
I thought you knew everything.
[crowd gasps and screams]
[clamouring]
Maia? Maia?
[mouse clicking]
[clamouring]
-Maia!
-[beeping]
[indistinct overlapping chatter]
-[caller] Jesus.
-[woman] Oh, my God!
-[woman] Holy shit!
-[laughs] Maia!
[Noah] Mummy!
["Delilah" playing]
Are you here?
[song continues muffled]
[Maia exhales]
[boatman] What the hell
are you doing up here?
I need you to take me
to London Bridge, south side.
[panting]
But if you don't get me there
in six minutes,
my son will be dead.
[woman]
♪ My, my, my, Delilah ♪
♪ Why, why, why, Delilah? ♪
♪ So before ♪
[inaudible]
♪ They come
To break down the door ♪
I'll take her.
♪ Forgive me, Delilah ♪
♪ I just couldn't take
Any more ♪
[TV reporter] As you can see,
security is already heavy
here at the Old Bailey
as the legal teams begin to arrive
for Tommy Boyd's murder trial.
Tantalisingly, we're hearing reports
of a surprise witness
inside Mr Boyd's organisation,
whose testimony is said to be devastating
for the alleged criminal kingpin.
Back to you, Mike, for the weather.
See the HMS Belfast up ahead?
I can get us near enough
for you to jump onto the jetty
but I can't stop.
Can you do that?
-Take the starboard door.
-Thank you.
I broke your special rules,
your stupid freaking rules.
[caller] Rules are made to be broken.
This is the end game.
[indistinct chatter]
[Maia grunts]
[man] …Belfast, beautiful day for it.
-It's a pride…
-[Maia grunts]
[suspenseful music playing]
[panting]
[timer beeping]
[Maia] They're here, the security detail,
getting ready to move him.
[caller] No time to waste, then.
Noah's breathing is getting shallow.
I got this. Okay.
[music fades]
["The Entertainer" playing]
[breathing heavily]
You're here, aren't you?
-["The Entertainer" distorts]
-[eerie music plays]
[caller] There are 267 rooms
in this establishment.
Could you find a Noah in the haystack?
Do your job, then you'll get
the room number.
Er, excuse me, madam,
may I ask where you're going?
I'm visiting a client,
Imperial Suite, 53rd floor.
Just one moment, please.
No, no, no, no.
Listen, listen, listen, sir,
I don't have time for this.
-I have a Ms…
-I don't have time for this.
I need to go upstairs, please.
-What's your name, please?
-Maia Marten.
-It's an emergency.
-Yes, okay.
-Sir.
That's fine.
You can go up now, Ms Marten.
-Have a good day, madam.
-[timer beeping]
[lift bell dings]
-[caller] Check the gun.
-[pouch unzips]
-[cartridge clatters]
-[panting]
Open your phone so I can see you.
A little reminder of what's at stake.
[stifles sob]
Now put it back on your arm,
facing forward.
I need to see you do this
with my own eyes.
[Maia breathing deeply]
[timer beeping]
[suspenseful music playing]
[lift bell dings]
-[liquid drips]
-[timer clicks]
-Morning.
-[guard] Good morning, ma'am.
I need to have a last-minute
chat with my client.
Been for a run, ma'am?
Have I ever.
You should get that cut seen to, ma'am.
[commentator] It was a really
difficult chance,
diving forward.
He just couldn't quite get
his fingers under the ball.
He did well to stop it, to be fair.
[timer clicks]
-[knocks]
-[Tafa] Come in.
Hello, Maia.
-[locks door]
-Do you like my new suit?
I got it for the big day.
You look like shit.
Maia?
Wait, wait. What you doing?
-[gunshot]
-[Tafa yells]
[gunshots]
[Tafa groans]
[Maia panting]
[guard] What's going on?
Ma'am, open the door!
-[knocking at door]
-[message alerts ping]
[guard shouting indistinctly]
[door opens, closes]
[alarm blaring]
[overlapping chatter]
[people clamouring]
[Maia] Let me through! Out of my way!
-Let me through!
-[woman gasps]
[man] Come on, darling, let's go!
-Come on.
-Out of my way! Out of my way!
[people clamouring]
-[alarm blaring]
-[Maia panting]
[grunts]
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Okay, Noah, wake up!
Mummy's here. Wake up.
Noah, wake up! [breathing heavily]
Noah. Noah.
Noah! Come on. Wake up.
Noah, come on! [grunts]
Noah, monkey, please don't leave me.
Come back!
[sobs]
[whispers] Wake up, baby.
[sobs gently]
[melancholic music playing]
[sobbing]
-[Noah, weakly] Mummy.
-[gasps]
[Maia sobs]
Hey, baby.
-Mum, I'm thirsty.
-[sobs]
I'll get you anything. [inhales sharply]
I'll get you anything.
I'm so sorry.
I love you so much.
[sobs]
[indistinct chatter]
[clamouring]
[officer] Move back, sir!
[man 1] Do you know what's happening?
[man 2] I don't know.
[Maia shushes]
Ms Marten.
DCI Philips.
He's still here, isn't he?
The building's locked down.
Only emergency services
are allowed in and out.
We're hoping the boy can identify him.
He doesn't remember anything.
[voice whispers] Killer.
-Maia? Maia?
-[officer] Sir, sir, stop!
Can I please…
Can I please just talk to them?
Sir, I have to ask you to
step away from the suspects.
[Maia] Noah,
this is Ted, my friend.
You're a brave boy.
There's something else. Ted, would you…
Of course. We'll get you
checked out by a paramedic.
Mum.
It's okay. I'll just be a few minutes.
[Ted] You all right?
-[Noah] Yeah, I'm fine.
-[Ted] Okay.
He said he has a contingency plan,
that it's going to be messy
and a lot of people are going to get hurt.
I think he has a bomb.
[Philips] Let's alert EOD of a code black.
[indistinct radio chatter]
[tense music playing]
[gasps] No!
[officer] Stay back!
[clamouring]
I'm just giving him
another dose of glucagon.
I'm so sorry. I think I was…
I'm losing my mind.
Don't worry.
Mum, I need to pee.
Constable Thompson.
[Thompson] Wait here
while I check out the toilets.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Maia] Noah?
It's him! Open the door! He's here!
Open the door!
[Maia breathing heavily]
[officer] Move back, please.
Witness coming through.
Let's move back, please.
[Maia] Ninety-nine percent
of defending yourself
is controlling the narrative.
[tape rewinding]
[phone ringing]
Please give me another chance.
[caller] You have 15 minutes.
[Maia] Thank you.
Er, excuse me, madam.
[gun clicks]
[gunshots]
[chuckles] I deserve a bloody award.
[people screaming]
I'm not a killer.
[officer 1] Shots fired! Shots fired!
[officer 2] Stay where you are!
Show us your hands!
-Hey!
-[officer 3] Get down!
-[officer 2] Take the bag.
-[officer 3] Take the bag.
Secure the bag. Secure the bag.
Stop struggling and get down.
[officer 1] Suspect has been identified.
[officer 3] All clear, all clear.
Bomb decommissioned.
[suspenseful music playing]
[music fades]
[reporter] The testimony of
key witness Radian Tafa
was devastating for the defence.
Tafa tied Mr Boyd and his associates
to the murders of Miss Summerhill
and Miss Patel.
It appears that justice
is at hand for the families
of these two innocent young women.
It's hard to see how Mr Boyd can escape
from a lengthy prison term.
[female reporter] Maia! Ms Marten!
[reporters clamouring]
[reporter 1] Can you give me
an official statement?
[reporter 2] Look this way.
You know, I don't know anyone else
who could have pulled this off.
I just told him the story
he wanted to believe.
[Ted] That old lawyer's trick.
Thanks, Ted.
Least I could do.
I'll drop by tomorrow,
early afternoon, just to check up on you.
[both chuckle]
Okay, you ready?
[Noah] Yeah.
[sombre music playing]
Oh, your backpack's gone. But…
-[Noah gasps] Red Ranger!
-[chuckles]
[mobile phone ringing]
[automated voice] Unknown caller calling.
Unknown caller calling.
[ringing stops]
[woman]
♪ I'm in the phone booth ♪
♪ It's the one
Across the hall ♪
♪ If you don't answer ♪
♪ I'll just ring it
Off the wall ♪
♪ I know he's there
But I just had to call ♪
["Hanging on the Telephone" playing]
♪ Don't leave me
Hanging on the telephone ♪
♪ I heard your mother
Now she's going out the door ♪
♪ Did she go to work
Or just go to the store? ♪
♪ All those things she said
I told you to ignore ♪
♪ Oh, why can't
We talk again? ♪
♪ Don't leave me
Hanging on the telephone ♪
♪ It's good to hear your voice
And stop this conversation ♪
♪ Your voice across the line
Gives me a strange sensation ♪
♪ I'd like to talk when I can
Show you my affection ♪
♪ Oh, I can't control myself ♪
♪ Don't leave me
Hanging on the telephone ♪
♪ Hang up and run to me ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh, whoa, whoa,
Whoa, run to me, yeah ♪
[song ends]
[unsettling music playing]
["The Entertainer" playing]